<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><entity>
  <logicalTable>
    <content>
      <header>
        <cell>
          <html>Year</html>
          <wikipedia/>
        </cell>
        <cell>
          <html>Nation</html>
          <wikipedia/>
        </cell>
        <cell>
          <html>Winning Drivers/Co-Drivers</html>
          <wikipedia/>
        </cell>
        <cell>
          <html>Car Used</html>
          <wikipedia/>
        </cell>
        <cell>
          <html>Nation</html>
          <wikipedia/>
        </cell>
      </header>
      <row>
        <cell>
          <html>1950</html>
          <wikipedia/>
        </cell>
        <cell>
          <html>../../../../images/shared/thumb/a/a4/Flag_of_the_United_States.svg/22px-Flag_of_the_United_States.svg.png USA</html>
          <wikipedia/>
        </cell>
        <cell>
          <html>Hershel McGriff / Ray Elliott</html>
          <wikipedia/>
        </cell>
        <cell>
          <html>Oldsmobile</html>
          <wikipedia/>
        </cell>
        <cell>
          <html>../../../../images/shared/thumb/a/a4/Flag_of_the_United_States.svg/22px-Flag_of_the_United_States.svg.png USA</html>
          <wikipedia/>
        </cell>
      </row>
      <row>
        <cell>
          <html>1951</html>
          <wikipedia/>
        </cell>
        <cell>
          <html>../../../../images/shared/thumb/0/03/Flag_of_Italy.svg/22px-Flag_of_Italy.svg.png Italy</html>
          <wikipedia/>
        </cell>
        <cell>
          <html>Piero Taruffi / Luigi Chinetti</html>
          <wikipedia/>
        </cell>
        <cell>
          <html>Ferrari</html>
          <wikipedia>Ferrari</wikipedia>
        </cell>
        <cell>
          <html>../../../../images/shared/thumb/0/03/Flag_of_Italy.svg/22px-Flag_of_Italy.svg.png Italy</html>
          <wikipedia/>
        </cell>
      </row>
      <row>
        <cell>
          <html>1952</html>
          <wikipedia/>
        </cell>
        <cell>
          <html>../../../../images/shared/thumb/b/ba/Flag_of_Germany.svg/22px-Flag_of_Germany.svg.png Germany</html>
          <wikipedia/>
        </cell>
        <cell>
          <html>Karl Kling / Hans Klenk</html>
          <wikipedia/>
        </cell>
        <cell>
          <html>Mercedes-Benz</html>
          <wikipedia/>
        </cell>
        <cell>
          <html>../../../../images/shared/thumb/b/ba/Flag_of_Germany.svg/22px-Flag_of_Germany.svg.png Germany</html>
          <wikipedia/>
        </cell>
      </row>
      <row>
        <cell>
          <html>1953</html>
          <wikipedia/>
        </cell>
        <cell>
          <html>../../../../images/shared/thumb/1/1a/Flag_of_Argentina.svg/22px-Flag_of_Argentina.svg.png Argentina</html>
          <wikipedia/>
        </cell>
        <cell>
          <html>Juan Manuel Fangio</html>
          <wikipedia>Juan_Manuel_Fangio</wikipedia>
        </cell>
        <cell>
          <html>Lancia</html>
          <wikipedia>Lancia</wikipedia>
        </cell>
        <cell>
          <html>../../../../images/shared/thumb/0/03/Flag_of_Italy.svg/22px-Flag_of_Italy.svg.png Italy</html>
          <wikipedia/>
        </cell>
      </row>
      <row>
        <cell>
          <html>1954</html>
          <wikipedia/>
        </cell>
        <cell>
          <html>../../../../images/shared/thumb/0/03/Flag_of_Italy.svg/22px-Flag_of_Italy.svg.png Italy</html>
          <wikipedia/>
        </cell>
        <cell>
          <html>Umberto Maglioli</html>
          <wikipedia>Umberto_Maglioli</wikipedia>
        </cell>
        <cell>
          <html>Ferrari</html>
          <wikipedia>Ferrari</wikipedia>
        </cell>
        <cell>
          <html>../../../../images/shared/thumb/0/03/Flag_of_Italy.svg/22px-Flag_of_Italy.svg.png Italy</html>
          <wikipedia/>
        </cell>
      </row>
    </content>
    <tableContext>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>Carrera Panamericana - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>[ edit ] Winners</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>Carrera Panamericana</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>As the 20th (XXth) anniversary of the race's recreation, 2007 saw Mr. Camargo gave thanks to the committee which has for 19 years organised the race, and the presence of President of the Mexican Motorsports Federation, Jose Sanchez Jassen, and President of the Mexican Rally Commission, Rafael Machado [20] . During the conference announcing the route, special mention was reserved for the efforts of Mexican law enforcement in general and of the Highway Patrol in particular, under the command of Comandante Julio Cesar Tovar, and to thank Mexican Federal, State and municipal authorities for collaborating to ensure smooth running of a challenging project.</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>[ edit ] External links</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>[ edit ] 1950</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>[ edit ] 1951</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>[ edit ] 1952</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>[ edit ] 1953</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>[ edit ] 1954</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>[ edit ] Cancellation</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>[ edit ] Legacy</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>[ edit ] 1988 Onwards</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>[ edit ] 2006</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>[ edit ] 2007</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>[ edit ] Winners</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>[ edit ] External links</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>Contents</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>The 2007 event, according to Eduardo Le n Camargo (President emeritus of La Carrera Panamericana), was the largest recreation to date. More than 100 teams (20 more than the usual limit) participated in seven days of racing from October 26th to November 1st inclusive, with an additional pre-qualifying stage held outside Oaxaca on Thursday October 25th [19] . Cars competed in the usual ten classes along a 3,100-kilometre (1,900 mi) course starting in Oaxaca. From there, the route lead the convoy in day-long sections consecutively between Tehuacan, Puebla, Queretaro, Morelia, Aguascalientes, Zacatecas and Nuevo Laredo.</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>[ edit ] 2007</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>Wikimedia Commons has media related to:</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>Also importantly, 2006 saw the debut of a 'modern' category, with the sole entry of a Lotus Elise ('Chica Loca') run by Rachel Larratt. This class, called Unlimited [17] , allows machines manufactured after 1990 to compete in the race. Controversially, in recognition of the high value of some of the supercars thus allowed to run, organisers of the race foresee the need to allow case-by-case exceptions from the race's normal safety equipment rules [18] . The class is intended to raise the race's profile beyond a market elderly enough to recall the original four races, to ensure the survival of the event. Also, it is a reflection of the increasing scarcity of eligible vehicles, and of the effect of modern rallies like the Gumball 3000 .</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>In a retro step, Cadillac entered a replica of the 1954 Series 62 coupe that a Colorado Springs dealer loaned to "five ordinary guys from Chicago", in order to revive a half-century old duel with Lincoln [16] . The original rag-tag team won the last two stages, and finished third in class (a Lincoln Capri won the Large Stock Class). The newer car, built in-house by GM's Performance Division Garage, preproduction trim shop and show-car paint department, was built from an identical coupe hauled from somewhere within Cadillac's own inventory. The 331-cubic-inch 270 hp (200 kW) V8 was enlarged to 398-cubic-inches, with higher 10.5:1 compression bringing output to 375 hp (280 kW) and 400 lb ft (540 N m) of torque, and certain safety improvements included. The car was reunited with Blu Plemons, the co-driver of the original (the driver, Keith Anderson, was killed in practice for the 1957 Indy 500 ) at the starting line. Among the nine other entries in the "Original Pan-Am" class were four Lincolns, including a 1949 model that contested the original Pan-Am.</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>The 2006 event started in Veracruz on the Gulf of Mexico coast, pulling in at Mexico City's CP circuit as a curtain raiser for the Champ Car race, and stayed nights at the old colonial cities Puebla, Queretaro, Morelia, Aguascalientes and Zacatecas, with the finish at modern Monterrey. It was won by Gabriel Perez and Angelica Fuentes in a yellow 1959 Ford Coupe, the first win for a woman and a first for the 'Turismo Production' class. Though competed mostly by amateurs, Jo Ramirez of the McLaren F1 team competed a Volvo P1800 amongst other star drivers.</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>[ edit ] 2006</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>The above is a clue as to what separates the Panamericana from other modern road races; it remains extremely dangerous. Mechanical attrition for the more classic cars often leads to burst brake lines and overheated engines, but crashes are also common on the winding roads. In 2006, a 19-year-old co-driver was left in a coma after his Jaguar E-Type Roadster crashed more than 100 ft (30 m) into a pine forest; Rusty Ward, another competitor, rolled a Studebaker from a bridge into a river, having finished the event in a similar fashion the previous year. It is obvious, therefore, that the race should not be classed with road-rallies in the style of the recreated Mille Miglia; the race is competitive with no speed restrictions on the closed-road sections.</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>Categories :</text>
      </context>
    </tableContext>
  </logicalTable>
</entity>
