<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><entity>
  <logicalTable>
    <content>
      <header>
        <cell>
          <html>Prefect</html>
          <wikipedia/>
        </cell>
        <cell>
          <html>Tenure</html>
          <wikipedia/>
        </cell>
        <cell>
          <html>Emperor served</html>
          <wikipedia/>
        </cell>
      </header>
      <row>
        <cell>
          <html>Cornelius Laco</html>
          <wikipedia>Cornelius_Laco</wikipedia>
        </cell>
        <cell>
          <html>68 - 69</html>
          <wikipedia/>
        </cell>
        <cell>
          <html>Galba</html>
          <wikipedia>Galba</wikipedia>
        </cell>
      </row>
      <row>
        <cell>
          <html>Plotius Firmus</html>
          <wikipedia>/w/index.php?title=Plotius_Firmus&amp;action=edit&amp;redlink=1</wikipedia>
        </cell>
        <cell>
          <html>69 - 69</html>
          <wikipedia/>
        </cell>
        <cell>
          <html>Otho</html>
          <wikipedia>Otho</wikipedia>
        </cell>
      </row>
      <row>
        <cell>
          <html>Licinius Proculus</html>
          <wikipedia>/w/index.php?title=Licinius_Proculus&amp;action=edit&amp;redlink=1</wikipedia>
        </cell>
        <cell>
          <html>69 - 69</html>
          <wikipedia/>
        </cell>
        <cell>
          <html>Otho</html>
          <wikipedia>Otho</wikipedia>
        </cell>
      </row>
      <row>
        <cell>
          <html>Publius Sabinus</html>
          <wikipedia>/w/index.php?title=Publius_Sabinus&amp;action=edit&amp;redlink=1</wikipedia>
        </cell>
        <cell>
          <html>69 - 69</html>
          <wikipedia/>
        </cell>
        <cell>
          <html>Vitellius</html>
          <wikipedia>Vitellius</wikipedia>
        </cell>
      </row>
      <row>
        <cell>
          <html>Alfenius Varus</html>
          <wikipedia>/w/index.php?title=Alfenius_Varus&amp;action=edit&amp;redlink=1</wikipedia>
        </cell>
        <cell>
          <html>69 - 69</html>
          <wikipedia/>
        </cell>
        <cell>
          <html>Vitellius</html>
          <wikipedia>Vitellius</wikipedia>
        </cell>
      </row>
      <row>
        <cell>
          <html>Junius Priscus</html>
          <wikipedia>/w/index.php?title=Junius_Priscus&amp;action=edit&amp;redlink=1</wikipedia>
        </cell>
        <cell>
          <html>69 - 69</html>
          <wikipedia/>
        </cell>
        <cell>
          <html>Vitellius</html>
          <wikipedia>Vitellius</wikipedia>
        </cell>
      </row>
    </content>
    <tableContext>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>Praetorian prefect - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>[ edit ] Year of the Four Emperors</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>Praetorian prefect</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>[ edit ] Julio-Claudian dynasty</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>[ edit ] Flavian dynasty</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>[ edit ] History</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>[ edit ] List of known prefects of the Praetorian Guard</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>[ edit ] Notes</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>[ edit ] References</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>Contents</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>The following is a list of all known prefects of the Praetorian Guard, from the establishment of the post in 2 BC by Augustus until the abolishment of the Guard in 314 . The list is presumed to be incomplete due to lack of sources documenting the exact number of persons who held the post, what their names were and what the length of their tenure was. Likewise, the Praetorians were sometimes commanded by a single prefect, as was the case with for example Sejanus or Burrus , but more often, the emperor appointed two commanders, who shared joint leadership. Overlapping terms on the list indicate dual command.</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>[ edit ] List of known prefects of the Praetorian Guard</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>[ edit ] Nervan-Antonian dynasty</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>The office was among the many maintained after the Western Roman empire had succombed to the Germanic invasion in Italy, notably at the royal court of the Ostrogothic king Theoderic the Great .</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>[ edit ] Germanic era</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>Under Constantine the Great , the institution of the magister militum deprived the praetorian prefecture altogether of its military character but left it the highest civil office of the empire.</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>[ edit ] Severan dynasty</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>The tetrarchy reform of Diocletian (c. 296) multiplied the office, as there was now one pretorian prefect as chief of staff (military and administrative) rather than commander of the guard for each of the two Augusti and two Caesares. Each one of the pretorian perfects oversaw one of the four quarters created by Diocletian, which would become praetorian prefectures under Constantine. Their masters were soon reduced to two imperial courts, at Rome (later Ravenna ) and Constantinople , but the four prefectures remained as the highest level of administrative division, in charge of several so-called dioceses (groups of Roman provinces ), each of which was headed by a Vicarius .</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>In addition to his military functions, the praetorian prefect came to acquire jurisdiction over criminal affairs, which he exercised not as the delegate but as the representative of the emperor. It was decreed by Constantine 331 that from the sentence of the praetorian praefect there should be no appeal. A similar jurisdiction in civil cases was acquired by him not later than the time of Septimius Severus . Hence a knowledge of law became a qualification for the post, which under Marcus Aurelius and Commodus , but especially from the time of Severus , was held by the first jurists of the age, (e.g. Papinian , Ulpian , Paullus ) and John the Cappadocian , while the military qualification fell more and more into the background.</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>[ edit ] Crisis of the Third Century</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>The insignia of the praetorian prefect of Illyricum, as depicted in the Notitia Dignitatum .</text>
      </context>
      <context>
        <score>1.0</score>
        <text>[ edit ] Transformation to administrator Further information: Praetorian prefecture</text>
      </context>
    </tableContext>
  </logicalTable>
</entity>
